Guide to the Duke Gardens Foundation records, 1912-2002 and undated
Duke University. University Archives
- Architectural Records, 1912-1982 and undated (Box 119)
  - [Frame of Greenhouse 24]. [Circa 1911]. Diazo. (Opaperfolder C2D7F2, Box 119)
  - [General Layout of Gardens Complex]. 1966. Pen. (Opaperfolder C2D7F2, Box 119)
  - [Sketch]. Undated. Pencil and watercolor. (Opaperfolder C2D7F2, Box 119)
  - [6" Water Main]. Undated. Pencil. (Opaperfolder C2D7F2, Box 119)
  - [Orchid Range & Surrounding Structures]. Undated. Negative photostat; photocopy. (Opaperfolder C2D7F2, Box 119)
  - [Flower Bed Plan]. Undated. Photocopy. (Opaperfolder C2D7F2, Box 119)
  - [Tree Layout]. Undated. Photocopy. (Opaperfolder C2D7F2, Box 119)
  - [Tree Layout]. Undated. Photocopy. (Opaperfolder C2D7F2, Box 119)
  - [Flower Layout]. Undated. Photocopy. (Opaperfolder C2D7F2, Box 119)
  - [Greenhouse Elevation]. Undated. Pencil. (Opaperfolder C2D7F2, Box 119)
  - Site Plan & Section [Orchid range]. Horowitz & Wirth/ M.M.S. 1977 Dec 22. Diazo; photocopy. (Opaperfolder C2D7F2, Box 119)
  - Detail for feature in garden of Duke Farms. Innocenti & Webel. Undated. Blueprint. (Opaperfolder C2D7F2, Box 119)
  - Duke Garden Greenhouse (sign). Rado. Undated. Pen and watercolor. (Opaperfolder C2D7F2, Box 119)
  - Preliminary Key Map-Secteur Position. Montrom LTD. 1971 Jun. Diazo. (Opaperfolder C2D10F1, Box 119)
  - Site Plan/Key Map. Montrom LTD. 1971 Jun. Diazo. (Opaperfolder C2D10F1, Box 119)
  - Decorative Wall Arcade. Montrom LTD. 1971 Jun. Diazo. (Opaperfolder C2D10F1, Box 119)
  - Heating Openings 3 Solutions. Montrom LTD. 1971 Jun. Diazo. (Opaperfolder C2D10F1, Box 119)
  - Partition Wall #2. Montrom LTD. 1971 Jun. Diazo. (Opaperfolder C2D10F1, Box 119)
  - Doris Duke Garden, Sector: Indo-Persia, Somerville, NJ, Partition Wall #1. Montrom LTD. 1971 Jul. Diazo. (Opaperfolder C2D10F1, Box 119)
  - Doris Duke Garden, Sector: Indo-Persia, Somerville, NJ, Left Wallside of Royal Door. Montrom LTD. 1971 Jul. Diazo. (Opaperfolder C2D10F1, Box 119)
  - Doris Duke Garden, Sector: Indo-Persia, Somerville, NJ, Decorative Wall Arcade. Montrom LTD. 1971 Jul. Diazo. (Opaperfolder C2D10F1, Box 119)
  - Doris Duke Garden, Sector: Indo-Persia, Somerville, NJ, Royal Door. Montrom LTD. 1971 Jul. Diazo. (Opaperfolder C2D10F1, Box 119)
  - Doris Duke Garden, Sector: Indo-Persia, Somerville, NJ, Royal Door Sections and Details. Montrom LTD. 1971 Jul. Diazo. (Opaperfolder C2D10F1, Box 119)
  - Doris Duke Garden, Sector: Indo-Persia, Somerville, NJ, Decorative Wall. Montrom LTD. 1971 Jul. Diazo. (Opaperfolder C2D10F1, Box 119)
  - Doris Duke Garden, Sector: Indo-Persia, Somerville, NJ, Decorative Wall Partition. Montrom LTD. 1971 Jul. Diazo. (Opaperfolder C2D10F1, Box 119)
  - Doris Duke Garden, Sector: Indo-Persia, Somerville, NJ, Entrance: Arcade. Montrom LTD. 1971 Jul. Diazo. (Opaperfolder C2D10F1, Box 119)
  - Doris Duke Garden, Sector: Indo-Persia, Somerville, NJ, Entrance Partition. Montrom LTD. 1971 Jul. Diazo. (Opaperfolder C2D10F1, Box 119)
  - Doris Duke Garden, Sector: Indo-Persia, Somerville, NJ, Column Details. Montrom LTD. 1971 Jul. Diazo. (Opaperfolder C2D10F1, Box 119)
  - Doris Duke Garden, Sector: Indo-Persia, Somerville, NJ, Ornament and Cover Details. Montrom LTD. 1971 Jul. Diazo. (Opaperfolder C2D10F1, Box 119)
  - Preliminary Key Map-Secteur Position. Montrom LTD. 1971 Jun. Diazo. (Opaperfolder C2D10F2, Box 119)
  - Site Plan/Key Map. Montrom LTD. 1971 Jun. Diazo. (Opaperfolder C2D10F2, Box 119)
  - Decorative Wall Arcade. Montrom LTD. 1971 Jun. Diazo. (Opaperfolder C2D10F2, Box 119)
  - Partition Wall #2. Montrom LTD. 1971 Jun. Diazo. (Opaperfolder C2D10F2, Box 119)
  - Doris Duke Garden, Sector: Indo-Persia, Somerville, NJ, Partition Wall #1. Montrom LTD. 1971 Jul. Diazo. (Opaperfolder C2D10F2, Box 119)
  - Doris Duke Garden, Sector: Indo-Persia, Somerville, NJ, Left Wallside of Royal Door. Montrom LTD. 1971 Jul. Diazo. (Opaperfolder C2D10F2, Box 119)
  - Doris Duke Garden, Sector: Indo-Persia, Somerville, NJ, Decorative Wall Arcade. Montrom LTD. 1971 Jul. Diazo. (Opaperfolder C2D10F2, Box 119)
  - Doris Duke Garden, Sector: Indo-Persia, Somerville, NJ, Royal Door. Montrom LTD. 1971 Jul. Diazo. (Opaperfolder C2D10F2, Box 119)
  - Doris Duke Garden, Sector: Indo-Persia, Somerville, NJ, Royal Door Sections and Details. Montrom LTD. 1971 Jul. Diazo. (Opaperfolder C2D10F2, Box 119)
  - Doris Duke Garden, Sector: Indo-Persia, Somerville, NJ, Decorative Wall. Montrom LTD. 1971 Jul. Diazo. (Opaperfolder C2D10F2, Box 119)
  - Doris Duke Garden, Sector: Indo-Persia, Somerville, NJ, Decorative Wall Partition. Montrom LTD. 1971 Jul. Diazo. (Opaperfolder C2D10F2, Box 119)
  - Doris Duke Garden, Sector: Indo-Persia, Somerville, NJ, Entrance: Arcade. Montrom LTD. 1971 Jul. Diazo. (Opaperfolder C2D10F2, Box 119)
  - Doris Duke Garden, Sector: Indo-Persia, Somerville, NJ, Entrance Partition. Montrom LTD. 1971 Jul. Diazo. (Opaperfolder C2D10F2, Box 119)
  - Doris Duke Garden, Sector: Indo-Persia, Somerville, NJ, Column Details. Montrom LTD. 1971 Jul. Diazo. (Opaperfolder C2D10F2, Box 119)
  - Doris Duke Garden, Sector: Indo-Persia, Somerville, NJ, Ornament and Cover Details. Montrom LTD. 1971 Jul. Diazo. (Opaperfolder C2D10F2, Box 119)
  - Doris Duke Garden, Sector: Indo-Persia, Somerville, NJ, Royal Door Templats. Montrom LTD. 1971 Jul. Diazo. (Opaperfolder C2D10F2, Box 119)
  - Doris Duke Garden, Sector: Indo-Persia, Somerville, NJ, Royal Door Templat. Montrom LTD. 1971 Jul. Diazo. (Opaperfolder C2D10F2, Box 119)
  - Flagstone Details for Reception Center. Donald Pantel. 1962 Jan 5; approved 1962 Jan 8. Diazo. (Opaperfolder DGF1, Box 119)
  - Proposed Planting for French Garden. Innocenti & Webel. Undated. Diazo and colored pencil. (Opaperfolder DGF1, Box 119)
  - Alterations of Garage-Duke Gardens. James A. Jones, architect. 1959 Jun 17. Diazo. (Opaperfolder DGF1, Box 119)
  - Plot Plan for Duke Gardens Foundation. Lord & Burnham. 1959 May 7. Diazo with ink. (Opaperfolder DGF1, Box 119)
  - Proposed New Passage. Lord & Burnham. 1961 Apr 12. Diazo. (Opaperfolder DGF1, Box 119)
  - Heating Plan, Dwg. H-1. Lord & Burnham. 1959 Apr 10. Diazo. (Opaperfolder DGF1, Box 119)
  - Proposed 27FT Gro Mor with Special Base Anchor. Lord & Burnham. 1964 Jun 25. Diazo. (Opaperfolder DGF1, Box 119)
  - Plant Purchases. Undated. Graph paper. (Opaperfolder DGF1, Box 119)
  - Greenhouses-Plans & Sections. Horace M. Patrick, consulting Engineer. 1961 Jul 5. Diazo. (Opaperfolder DGF2, Box 119)
  - Parking Lot. Donald H. Stires. Undated. Diazo. (Opaperfolder DGF2, Box 119)
  - Stnd. RFAH-440V Transformer & Contactor-FP2 Electric Control. By L.G. 1961 Feb 6. Sepia diazo. (Opaperfolder DGF2, Box 119)
  - Proposal "A". Donald H. Stires. Undated. Sepia diazo with colored pencil. (Opaperfolder DGF2, Box 119)
  - Map of Survey, Residence & Maintenance Area Survey, Duke Gardens Foundation. Donald H. Stires Associates. 1964 Jul 10. Diazo. (Opaperfolder DGF2, Box 119)
  - General Construction Details for the Conservatory. Innocenti & Webel. 1959 Jan 20. Diazo with ink. (Opaperfolder DGF3, Box 119)
  - Framing Plan [Greenhouse] for J.B. Duke. Undated. Diazo. (Opaperfolder DGF3, Box 119)
  - Doris Duke Gardens, Secteur: Indo-Persia, Preliminary Key Map. Montrom Ltd. 1971 Jun. Diazo. (Opaperfolder DGF4, Box 119)
  - Doris Duke Gardens, Secteur: Indo-Persia, Preliminary Decorative Wall Arcade. Montrom Ltd. 1971 Jun. Diazo. (Opaperfolder DGF4, Box 119)
  - Doris Duke Gardens, Secteur: Indo-Persia, Preliminary Partition Wall. Montrom Ltd. 1971 Jun. Diazo. (Opaperfolder DGF4, Box 119)
  - Duke Gardens Foundation, Typical Grille Design on Garden Wall (Sheet 1 of 5). Richard C. Tongg, landscape architect. 1960 Apr 18. Diazo. (Opaperfolder DGF4, Box 119)
  - Duke Gardens Foundation, Balustrades Design for Duke Gardens Foundation (Sheet 2 of 5). Richard C. Tongg, landscape architect. 1960 Apr 25. Diazo. (Opaperfolder DGF4, Box 119)
  - Duke Gardens Foundation, Pavilion Grille Detail (Sheet 3 of 5). Richard C. Tongg, landscape architect. 1960 Apr 25. Diazo. (Opaperfolder DGF4, Box 119)
  - Duke Gardens Foundation, Pavilion & Moon Door Way Detail (Sheet 4 of 5). Richard C. Tongg, landscape architect. 1960 Apr 25. Diazo. (Opaperfolder DGF4, Box 119)
  - Duke Gardens Foundation, Pavilion Detail (Sheet 5 of 5). Richard C. Tongg, landscape architect. 1960 Apr 25. Diazo. (Opaperfolder DGF4, Box 119)
  - A Cactus Garden for Duke Farms. Richard C. Tongg, landscape architect. 1959 Aug 12. Diazo. (Opaperfolder DGF4, Box 119)
  - A Chinese Garden for Duke Farms. Richard C. Tongg, landscape architect. 1959 Aug 12. Diazo. (Opaperfolder DGF4, Box 119)
  - A Spanish Garden for Duke Farms. Richard C. Tongg, landscape architect. 1959 Aug 12. Diazo. (Opaperfolder DGF4, Box 119)
  - Plot Plan for Duke Gardens Foundation, Inc. Lord & Burnham. 1964 Apr 20. Diazo. (Opaperfolder DGF4, Box 119)
  - Plot Plan for Duke Gardens Foundation, Inc. Lord & Burnham. 1959 May 7, revised 1959 May 15. Diazo. (Opaperfolder DGF4, Box 119)
  - The New York Botanical Garden Preliminary Greenhouse Plan. C. Patton. [1964]. Sepia. (Opaperfolder DGF5, Box 119)
  - The New York Botanical Garden Preliminary Greenhouse Plan, Elevation Study. Robinson, Capsis, Stern Associates. [1964]. Sepia. (Opaperfolder DGF5, Box 119)
  - The New York Botanical Garden Preliminary Greenhouse Plan, Propogation Range Facility Study. Robinson, Capsis, Stern Associates. [1964]. Sepia. (Opaperfolder DGF5, Box 119)
  - The New York Botanical Garden Preliminary Greenhouse Plan, Growing Ranges Structure Study. Robinson, Capsis, Stern Associates. [1964]. Sepia. (Opaperfolder DGF5, Box 119)
  - The New York Botanical Garden Preliminary Greenhouse Plan, Sections of Various Arrangements. Robinson, Capsis, Stern Associates. [1964]. Sepia. (Opaperfolder DGF5, Box 119)
  - The New York Botanical Garden Preliminary Greenhouse Plan, Linier Range Housing. Robinson, Capsis, Stern Associates. [1964]. Sepia. (Opaperfolder DGF5, Box 119)
  - Exhibit System Detail Plan, New York State Exhibit Building, New York World's Fair, Levels 3 & 4, Sheet No. X-06-2. Robinson, Capsis, Stern Associates. 1964 Jan 30. Sepia. (Opaperfolder DGF5, Box 119)
  - Exhibit System Detail Plan, New York State Exhibit Building, New York World's Fair, Level 2, Sheet No. X-06-1. Robinson, Capsis, Stern Associates. 1964 Jan 30. Sepia. (Opaperfolder DGF5, Box 119)
  - Exhibit System Detail Plan, New York State Exhibit Building, New York World's Fair, Level 1, Sheet No. X-06-0. Robinson, Capsis, Stern Associates. 1964 Jan 30. Sepia. (Opaperfolder DGF5, Box 119)
  - Exhibit System Plan, Promenade Deck Level, New York State Exhibit Building, New York World's Fair, Sheet A-2. Robinson, Capsis, Stern Associates. 1963 Dec 16. Sepia. (Opaperfolder DGF5, Box 119)
  - Exhibit System Detail Typical Elements, Promenade Deck Level, New York State Exhibit Building, New York World's Fair, Sheet XT-1. Robinson, Capsis, Stern Associates. 1964 Feb 6. Sepia. (Opaperfolder DGF5, Box 119)
  - Detail of Welds. Robinson, Capsis, Stern Associates. 1964 Jan 29. Sepia. (Opaperfolder DGF5, Box 119)
  - Map of Survey Duke Gardens Foundation, Sheet 1. Donald H. Stires, professional engineer and land surveyor. 1961 May 15, revised 1961 May 19. Diazo. (Opaperfolder DGF6, Box 119)
  - Map of Survey Duke Gardens Foundation, Sheet 2. Donald H. Stires, professional engineer and land surveyor. 1961 May 19. Diazo. (Opaperfolder DGF6, Box 119)
  - Map of Survey Duke Gardens Foundation, Sheet 3. Donald H. Stires, professional engineer and land surveyor. 1961 Jul 8. Diazo. (Opaperfolder DGF6, Box 119)
  - Plan of Above & Below Ground Utilities, Duke Gardens, Sheet 5 of 11. Raritan Valley Engineering. 1964 Nov 12. Diazo. (Opaperfolder DGF6, Box 119)
  - Plan of Above & Below Ground Utilities, Duke Gardens, Sheet 6 of 11. Raritan Valley Engineering. 1964 Nov 12. Diazo. (Opaperfolder DGF6, Box 119)
  - Proposed Renovation to Desert Garden, Barrel Vault Detail Garden. Lord & Burnham. 1974 Sep 19. Diazo. (Opaperfolder DGF7, Box 119)
  - Proposed Renovation to Desert Garden, Perspective. Lord & Burnham. 1974 Sep 19. Diazo. (Opaperfolder DGF7, Box 119)
  - Proposed Greenhouse for Duke Gardens Foundation. Lord & Burnham. 1974 Oct 22. Diazo. (Opaperfolder DGF7, Box 119)
  - Cross Sections Proposed Renovations to Desert Garden House No. 4. Lord & Burnham. 1974 Mar 13. Diazo. (Opaperfolder DGF7, Box 119)
  - Perspective and Elevation, Proposed Renovations to Desert Garden House No. 4. Lord & Burnham. 1974 Mar 15. Diazo. (Opaperfolder DGF7, Box 119)
  - Proposed Barrel Vault Roof for Bank Building. Lord & Burnham. 1973 Nov 11. Diazo. (Opaperfolder DGF7, Box 119)
  - Side Details-Double Glazing Rigid Frame Construction. Lord & Burnham. 1975 Feb 26. Diazo. (Opaperfolder DGF7, Box 119)
  - Design A, Design B. H. Katakawa. Undated. Pencil on board. (Opaperfolder DGF8, Box 119)
  - Japanese Garden. Undated. Ink. (Opaperfolder DGF9, Box 119)
  - Project: Growing Gardens Reconstruction Phase III, Duke Gardens Foundation. Horowitz & Wirth. 1977 Dec 22. Diazo. (Opaperfolder DGF10, Box 119)
  - Floor Plan Palm House and Aquatic House. Horowitz & Wirth. 1976 Feb 20. Diazo. (Opaperfolder DGF10, Box 119)
  - Renovation to English Garden. Horowitz & Wirth. 1979 Nov 2. Diazo. (Opaperfolder DGF10, Box 119)
  - Gable Elevation at Japanese and Chinese Gardens. Roper IBG. 1975 Apr 17. Diazo. (Opaperfolder DGF10, Box 119)
  - Gable Elevation at House No. 2. Roper IBG. 1975 Apr 4. Diazo. (Opaperfolder DGF10, Box 119)
  - Site Plan Duke Gardens Foundation. URI. 1970 Apr 3. Diazo. (Opaperfolder DGF10, Box 119)
  - Climate Control System, Control Location Schematic. OCS. 1986 Feb 24. Diazo. (Opaperfolder DGF10, Box 119)
  - Map of Survey Duke Gardens Foundation (4 sheets). Donald H. Stires. 1964 Aug 15. Photocopy. (Opaperfolder DGF11, Box 119)
  - [Drawing Showing Stone Sills and Wood Sills], J.B. Duke Esq. Undated. Ink on linen. (Opaperfolder DGF11, Box 119)